# Abram Yoshida Front-End Engineer

(212) 865-4029 • (646) 573-1132 abeyoshida@gmail.com

#### **Summary**

Senior Front-End Engineer with a rare combination of artistic and technical expertise with an expert grasp of client side browser technologies. Background includes 20 years designing and developing websites to meet business needs for major financial and publishing corporations.

#### **Work Experience**

JPMorgan Chase, June 2015 to July 2017

Senior Front-End Engineer – Asset Management Document Management Group Created Angular.js and SASS/css code base for a corporate wide application that would provide document creation, tagging, retrieval capabilities for all legal documents and contracts.

# Sapient Corporation, May 2013 to May 2015

Senior Interactive Developer - Goldman Sachs AIMS project

Provide all front-end code requirements (html, css and javascript) for a Goldman Sachs Asset Management web application that gives clients the ability to match their interests and needs in diverse asset classes with specific Goldman Sachs managers who could provide targeted investment expertise.

Senior Interactive Engineer – J.P. Morgan AIS project

Provide semantic html markup and css for the J.P. Morgan development team that was building out the Alternative Investment Portal that provided comprehensive reporting and search capability for a diverse universe of traded assets.

Senior Interactive Engineer - Wiley Publications Quant Portal project

Create a clickable prototype for a web application in html, css and javascript that would allow pricing models for quants and financial industry experts to be searched, shared, and tested online.

The prototype code architecture relied on the angular.js MVC library.

## Conde Nast Digital, December 2012 to May 2013

Senior UI Engineer - Magazine Websites

UI Engineer supporting all front-end coding requirements for sites built on Conde Nast Digital's CQ5 platform. The supported sites include Vanity Fair, Glamour, Conde Nast Traveler, Lucky and Architectural Digest.

Extended CQ5 image rotator component for Architectural Digest using ExtJs and jQuery libraries.

## Gerson Lehrman Group, 2011 to 2012

UI Engineer - Social Network Portal

UI Engineer supporting all front end coding requirements for the GLG Research platform and G+ (gplus.com), a social networking website for expert Q & A.

- Developed a javascript and oocss mini framework for an SVG/VML library that displayed animated charts of member profile data.
- Developed a jQuery UI widget for the GLG Research platform to manage primary research queries.
- Interfaced with project managers, back-end developers, designers and QA.

## McGraw-Hill Higher Education, 2010 to 2011

UI Consultant - eCommerce Bookstore

UI web developer in the Higher Education Digital Group supporting all front-end development requirements (html, css, javascript) for McGraw-Hill's eBookstore, an online store that was a growing driver in revenue for McGraw-Hill's corporate initiative to add digital pathways to their existing educational assets.

- UI code responsibilities for eBookstore, an eCommerce, single-page RESTful web application using a proprietary javascript framework, heavy ajax functionality and iQuery.
- Extended the existing framework to include an administrative access layer to manage a user's view of eBookstore based on entitlement

#### TD Ameritrade, 2009 to 2010

Front End Consultant – eCommerce Trading Platform

Fulfilled client side development and coding requirements (html, css, javascript) to help build out the next generation online platform for retail and institutional clients.

- Created a code template for the Portfolio Allocation app using jQuery that integrated input from a redline document and functional prototype.
- Added new functionality to the Futures and Forex trading component that allowed clients to manage funds between different portfolios and accounts.
- Added client-side expertise to the server-side Java team that integrated visual design and UX requirements with the Java Jaguar back-end framework.

## Bear Stearns, 1999 to 2009

Managing Director, Ecommerce Developer

- Design, architecture and coding responsibilities (html, css, javascript) in building web sites and applications to help diverse business lines access ecommerce opportunities for growth, cost savings and operating efficiency.
- Designed and implemented the Best Markets website that brought Bear Stearns into a new structured investment market in Asia and Europe and gave prospective clients the ability to buy, sell and restructure hybrid investment instruments over the web based on real time pricing.
- Developed a SOA style web trading portal for the Cash Management Group that enabled all clients to manage their assets online. Functionality included grid displays of latest daily prices, filtering based on various criteria and authentication,

## Abram Yoshida, Senior Front-End Engineer

live buy/sell/redemption requests, live portfolio displays with recent activity status, live updates on trading rules and limits for each company and formatting for printing. SEO and Google Analytics methods added to code. Since the adoption of the web portal total assets under management increased by \$3 billion.

- Replaced costly Bloomberg terminals with an ajax web application (html, css, javascript) that delivered live market data via a Reuters data feed company wide that saved hundreds of thousands of dollars annually.
- Re-wrote the Bear Stearns' intranet code base to be aligned with web standards (html, css), unobtrusive javascript and SEO coding methods which led to productivity and efficiency gains for eCommerce developers.

#### Deutsche Bank, 1996 to 1999

Web Developer

 Provided html and css code for Women On Wall Street website. Added cgi capabilities with Perl to connect to an Excel spreadsheet through ODBC.

## Bankers Trust, 1992 to 1996

**Document Production Supervisor** 

 Supervised the production of Business Proposal Documents in company wide document production center. Updated graphic capabilities with new process for recreating raster image logos into vector image files.

#### **Skills**

Programming Languages ES6, Object Oriented Javascript, React, Angular, HTML5,

and Scripting CSS3, Bootstrap, Material Design for React, SASS, Git,

Webpack

**Applications** VS Code, Webstorm, Mercurial, SVN, Clearcase,

Fireworks, Photoshop, MS Office

#### **Education**

**University of Hawaii**, Honolulu, HI Masters of Fine Arts, Painting, 1980

**University of Hawaii**, Honolulu, HI Bachelors of Fine Arts, Painting 1975